Princeton Ethiopic Manuscripts, late 1600s-1900s: Finding Aid C0776
Manuscripts Division
- Princeton Ethiopic Manuscript No. 57: Miracles of Mary With Three Miracles of Saint George, mid 18th century; 57; 165 Leaves Mostly in numbered gatherings of 8 leaves, the manuscript is in excellent condition and shows no damage and only a little natural wear to the edges of some leaves, 1 col. of
  Date and provenance: Mid-18th century. There is no colophon giving the date of composition. However, the hand and style of the paintings are in keeping with a mid eighteenth century date. The invocations for blessings throughout the text are mostly made for one Lätes'un (m.) occasionally in conjunction with that Wälättä Täklä Haymanot (f.). However, the name Awsabyos (m.) has been inserted in the top margin of many leaves, and also appears alongside the picture of the prostrate supplicant in paintings 2, 54 and 55, though in the last instance the figure is clearly female.
  The text comprises 34 miracles of the Virgin Mary together with 3 miracles of St. George.
  Fol. 1r: Blank except for pen trial.
  Purchase, Sam Fogg, London.
  - Miracles of Mary, mid 18th century; multiple folios; Located on folio 5r-155r. (Unitid 57)
    - The Story of Hildefonsus of Toledo [Däqseyos], mid 18th century; multiple folios; Located on folio 5r-12r. (Unitid 57)
    - The Story of the Poor Monk Who Had Neither Food Nor Clothes, mid 18th century; multiple folios; Located on folio 13r-14v. (Unitid 57)
    - The Story of the Artisan Who Was Devoted to the Virgin Mary, mid 18th century; multiple folios; Located on folio 16r-18r. (Unitid 57)
    - The Story of the Jew of Akhmim, mid 18th century; multiple folios; Located on folio 19r-21v. (Unitid 57)
    - The Story of Damianus of Philippi [Demyanos of Felp'esyos], mid 18th century; multiple folios; Located on folio 23r-25v. (Unitid 57)
    - The Story of Pope Leon [Bishop Abbas of Romé], mid 18th century; multiple folios; Located on folio 26v-29v. (Unitid 57)
    - The Story of Isaac the Monk, mid 18th century; multiple folios; Located on folio 30v-34v. (Unitid 57)
    - The Story of the Man from Defra Whose Daughter Was Transported to Paradise, mid 18th century; multiple folios; Located on folio 36r-39r. (Unitid 57)
    - The Story of the Artist Who Fell from His Scaffolding, mid 18th century; multiple folios; Located on folio 40v-44r. (Unitid 57)
    - The Story of the Sick Merchant, mid 18th century; multiple folios; Located on folio 45r-47r. (Unitid 57)
    - The Story of the Young Man Zacharias [Zäkaryas], mid 18th century; multiple folios; Located on folio 49r-54r. (Unitid 57)
    - The Story of Juliana and Barbara [Yolyana and Bärbara], mid 18th century; multiple folios; Located on folio 55v-58r. (Unitid 57)
    - The Story of the Three Arabs of Rif, mid 18th century; multiple folios; Located on folio 59v-62v. (Unitid 57)
    - The Story of the Church that Was Transported to the Shores of the Sea of "Iyariko", mid 18th century; multiple folios; Located on folio 64r-66v. (Unitid 57)
    - The Story of the Blind Priest, Yohannes of Bäkänsi, mid 18th century; multiple folios; Located on folio 66v-71v. (Unitid 57)
    - The Story of the Rich Merchant of Qwälasyes, mid 18th century; multiple folios; Located on folio 72v-75v. (Unitid 57)
    - The Story of the Daughter of Abreham of Bedreman, mid 18th century; multiple folios; Located on folio 77r-81v. (Unitid 57)
    - The Story of the Poor Widow and Her Daughters, mid 18th century; multiple folios; Located on folio 83r-87r. (Unitid 57)
    - The Story of the Two Brother Scribes, mid 18th century; multiple folios; Located on folio 88v-91r. (Unitid 57)
    - The Story of George the Younger, mid 18th century; multiple folios; Located on folio 92v-94v. (Unitid 57)
    - The Story of the Priest Kät'ir of Elkus [sic], mid 18th century; multiple folios; Located on folio 96r-99v. (Unitid 57)
    - The Story of the Dyer Näzib, mid 18th century; multiple folios; Located on folio 101r-106r. (Unitid 57)
    - The Story of the Man With a Club Foot, mid 18th century; multiple folios; Located on folio 107v-111v. (Unitid 57)
    - The Story of Bishop Mercurius [Märqoréwos], mid 18th century; multiple folios; Located on folio 113r-115v. (Unitid 57)
    - The Story of the Woman of Haarlem [Hartälom], mid 18th century; multiple folios; Located on folio 117-120v. (Unitid 57)
    - The Story of Abbess Sophia of Carmel [Sofya of Qärmélos], mid 18th century; multiple folios; Located on folio 121r-129r. (Unitid 57)
    - The Story of Barok of Finqi, mid 18th century; multiple folios; Located on folio 129v-132r. (Unitid 57)
    - The Story of the Deacon Anastasius [Anest'asyos], mid 18th century; multiple folios; Located on folio 133r-134v. (Unitid 57)
    - The Story of the Monk Salusi of the Monastery of Qälmon, mid 18th century; multiple folios; Located on folio 135v-138r. (Unitid 57)
    - [bottom, Different hand] Short Hymn or Prayer, mid-1700s>, mid 18th century; multiple folios; Located on folio 138r. (Unitid 57)
    - The Story of the Cannibal of Qemer, mid 18th century; multiple folios; Located on folio 139r-142v. (Unitid 57)
    - The Story of the Widow's Son Who Was a Thief, mid 18th century; multiple folios; Located on folio 144v-146r. (Unitid 57)
    - The Story of the Woman Who Gave Birth in a Storm At Sea, mid 18th century; multiple folios; Located on folio 146v-149r. (Unitid 57)
    - The Story of the Thirsty Dog, mid 18th century; multiple folios; Located on folio 150r-152r. (Unitid 57)
    - The Story of the Five Sorrows Told by the Virgin to Her Son and His Granting of the Covenant of Mercy on Her Behalf, mid 18th century; multiple folios; Located on folio 153r-155r. (Unitid 57)
    - [bottom, Different hand] Prayer to the Virgin Mary, mid 18th century; multiple folios; Located on folio 155r. (Unitid 57)
  - Miracles of St. George, mid 18th century; multiple folios; Located on folio 156r-162v. (Unitid 57)
- Princeton Ethiopic Manuscript No. 58: Ethiopic Amulet, 1900s; 58; 1; In the form of a miniature book. Parchment leaves (2 flyleaves at front; 18 leaves in 3 quires), with trim dimensions of 3.5 x 2.5 cm. Original blind-tooled leather binding.; 3.5 x 2.5 cm (Unitid 58)
- Princeton Ethiopic Manuscript No. 59: Ethiopic Folding Picture Book, circa 1870-1930; 59; 1; On parchment. Comprised of 10 panels measuring approximately 50 x 50 cm each, opening horizontally; 50 x 50 cm (Unitid 59)
  The panels contain scenes of the life of Christ, with brief inscriptions in Ge'ez.
- Princeton Ethiopic Manuscript No. 60: Collection of Astrological and Divinatory Treatises, circa 1850-1899; 60; 29 folios 1 column [fols. 1-8, 12-13, 17v-22], 2 columns [fols. 9-11, 14, 23-29], 20-22 lines. Parchment. Composite manuscript, various hands. Wooden boards covered in stamped leather. Fol. 22v: Blank. 14.5 x 20 cm (Unitid 60)
  The eight paintings were all added later.
  Illustration: Fol. 15r: Painting 1: Figure representing the zodiacal sign Virgo (Sanbulā).
  Illustration: Fol. 15v: Painting 2: Figure representing the zodiacal sign Cancer (Sart'ān).
  Illustration: Fol. 16r: Painting 3: Figure representing the zodiacal sign Leo ('Asad).
  Illustration: Fol. 16v: Painting 4: Figure representing the zodiacal sign Sagittarius (Qaws).
  Illustration: Fol. 17r: Painting 5: Figure representing the zodiacal sign Libra (Mizān).
  Illustration: Fol. 21r: Painting 6: Eight-pointed star design with central face.
  Illustration: Fol. 22r: Painting 7: Nine round faces encircling two square faces.
  Illustration: Fol. 22r [bottom]: Painting 8: Two circles with central faces.
  Immediate Source of Acquisition
  Gift of Bruce Willsie, Class of 1986 (AM 2013-44).
  - Explanation of the Stars (Fekkārē Kawākebt), circa 1850-1899; multiple folios; Located on folio 1r-8v. (Unitid 60)
    An astrological treatise, in Ge'ez with sections in Amharic. Incomplete, terminates in abrupto.
  - Divinatory Interpretations of Signs and Prescriptions [different hand], circa 1850-1899; multiple folios; Located on folio 9r-11v, 14rv. (Unitid 60)
    In Amharic. Terminates in abrupto.
  - [Different hand], circa 1850-1899; multiple folios; Located on folio 12r-13v. (Unitid 60)
  - Prayers for Undoing Spells and against Various Ailments, With Talismanic Drawings [different hand], circa 1850-1899; multiple folios; Located on folio 17v-18v. (Unitid 60)
  - Further Divinations and Prescriptions, circa 1850-1899; multiple folios; Located on folio 19rv. (Unitid 60)
  - Magic Words and Phrases and Signs, circa 1850-1899; multiple folios; Located on folio 20r. (Unitid 60)
  - Series of Prayers against Budā, Qu[ra]ññā, Bāryā, etc. and Various Ailments, circa 1850-1899; multiple folios; Located on folio 20v-22r. (Unitid 60)
  - Further Divinations and Prescriptions [different hand], circa 1850-1899; multiple folios; Located on folio 23r-28r. (Unitid 60)
  - Prayer Titled "The Chariot of Elijah" (Saragallā 'Ēlyās) [different hand], circa 1850-1899; multiple folios; Located on folio 28rv. (Unitid 60)
  - Beginning of a Text Titled "The Epistles of Shem, Abraham and Isaac" [different Hand, and outlined], circa 1850-1899; multiple folios; Located on folio 28v. (Unitid 60)
  - Magical Prescriptions and Procedures [different Hand, in Amharic], circa 1850-1899; multiple folios; Located on folio 29rv. (Unitid 60)
- Princeton Ethiopic Manuscript No. 61: Homilies and Miracles of St. Michael, 1800s; 61; 184 folios 2 columns, 20-21 lines. Parchment. 20 Paintings (added later), 8 colored [harags] or ornamental headpieces. Wooden boards covered in stamped leather with brocade insert panels on the inside, hide slipcase. 19.5 x 26 cm (Unitid 61)
  The paintings and [harags] are all added later, the former in some cases apparently over text. There are also several [harags] drawn in pencil but not colored in. The paintings have been executed in an archaizing style by an accomplished artist, probably in the latter part of the 20th century.
  Illustration: Fol. 1r: Painting 1: The Annunciation.
  Illustration: Fol. 1v: Painting 2: The Nativity of Jesus.
  Illustration: Fol. 2r: Painting 3: God the Father, the Son and the Holy Ghost crowning Mary.
  Illustration: Fol. 2v: Painting 4: The Baptism of Jesus by John.
  Illustration: Fol. 3r: Painting 5: Jesus fasting in the desert, tempted by the Devil.
  Illustration: Fol. 3v: Painting 6: Our Lady Mary and Elizabeth.
  Illustration: Fol. 4r: Painting 7: The Virgin Mary giving Daqseyos a throne and a cloak in return for his having written the Book of her Miracles (a scene drawn from the Miracles of Mary text).
  Illustration: Fol. 4v: Painting 8: St. Mark the Evangelist.
  Illustration: Fol. 32v: Painting 9: St. Gabriel saving the three children from the fiery furnace.
  Illustration: Fol. 58v: Painting 10: The Resurrection of Our Lord, with the figures of Adam and Eve.
  Illustration: Fol. 67r: Painting 11: Herod ordering the execution of James the brother of John.
  Illustration: Fol. 107v: Painting 12: Jesus raising the widow's son.
  Illustration: Fol. 130r: Painting 13: Jesus healing the blind man at Bethsaida.
  Illustration: Fol. 139v: Painting 14: St. George slaying the dragon.
  Illustration: Fol. 154v: Painting 15: Mary prostrating herself before Our Lord.
  Illustration: Fol. 162r: Painting 16: Jesus raising Lazarus.
  Illustration: Fol. 177r: Painting 17: The Crucifixion.
  Illustration: Fol. 183v: Painting 18: Joseph and Nicodemus placing Jesus in the tomb.
  Illustration: Fol. 184r: Painting 19: The Deposition from the Cross.
  Illustration: Fol. 184v: Painting 20: St. Michael the Archangel.
  Former owners: Walda 'Iyasus and Walatta Heywat, also Hāyla Mikā'ēl
  - History of St. Michael the Archangel (Zēnā ... Qeddus Mikā'ēl Liqa Malā'ekt), 1800s; multiple folios; Located on folio 5r-11v. (Unitid 61)
  - Homily of St. Michael for the 12th of Hedār (Nov. 21) by Abbā Damātēwos of Alexandria, 1800s; multiple folios; Located on folio 12r-25v. (Unitid 61)
    - Prayers to St. Michael, 1800s; multiple folios; Located on folio 26r-28r. (Unitid 61)
    - A Miracle of St. Michael, 1800s; multiple folios; Located on folio 28r-30r. (Unitid 61)
    - Synaxarium Entry for the 12th of Hedār, 1800s; multiple folios; Located on folio 30r-32r. (Unitid 61)
  - Homily of St. Michael for the 12th of Tāhsās (Dec. 21), 1800s; multiple folios; Located on folio 33r-41r. (Unitid 61)
    - A Miracle of St. Michael, 1800s; multiple folios; Located on folio 41r-43r. (Unitid 61)
    - Synaxarium Entry for the 12th of Tāhsās, 1800s; multiple folios; Located on folio 43v-44r. (Unitid 61)
  - Homily of St. Michael for the 12th of T'er (Jan. 20), 1800s; multiple folios; Located on folio 44v-56r. (Unitid 61)
    - A Miracle of St. Michael, 1800s; multiple folios; Located on folio 56r-58r. (Unitid 61)
    - Synaxarium Entry for the 12th of T'er, 1800s; multiple folios; Located on folio 58r. (Unitid 61)
  - Homily of St. Michael for the 12th of Yakkātit (Feb. 19), 1800s; multiple folios; Located on folio 59r-63r. (Unitid 61)
    - A Miracle of St. Michael, 1800s; multiple folios; Located on folio 63r-65r. (Unitid 61)
    - Synaxarium Entry for the 12th of Yakkātit, 1800s; multiple folios; Located on folio 65r-67r. (Unitid 61)
  - Homily of St. Michael for the 12th of Maggābit (Mar. 21) by John Bishop of Antioch, 1800s; multiple folios; Located on folio 67v-86v. (Unitid 61)
    - A Miracle of St. Michael, 1800s; multiple folios; Located on folio 87r-90r. (Unitid 61)
    - Synaxarium Entry for the 12th of Maggābit, 1800s; multiple folios; Located on folio 90r. (Unitid 61)
  - Homily of St. Michael for the 12th of Miyāzyā (Apr. 20) by "the Orthodox" (Retu'a Haymānot), 1800s; multiple folios; Located on folio 90v-96r. (Unitid 61)
    - A Miracle of St. Michael, 1800s; multiple folios; Located on folio 96r-99v. (Unitid 61)
    - Synaxarium Entry for the 12th of Miyāzyā, 1800s; multiple folios; Located on folio 100rv. (Unitid 61)
  - Homily of St. Michael for the 12th of Genbot (May 20) by John Bishop of Ethiopia, 1800s; multiple folios; Located on folio 101r-103v. (Unitid 61)
    - A Miracle of St. Michael, 1800s; multiple folios; Located on folio 103v-106v. (Unitid 61)
    - Synaxarium Entry for the 12th of Genbot, 1800s; multiple folios; Located on folio 106v-107r. (Unitid 61)
  - Homily of St. Michael for the 12th of Sanē (June 19) by the Bishop of Axum, 1800s; multiple folios; Located on folio 108r-115v. (Unitid 61)
    - A Miracle of St. Michael, 1800s; multiple folios; Located on folio 115v-119r. (Unitid 61)
    - Synaxarium Entries for the 12th of Sanē, 1800s; multiple folios; Located on folio 119r-129v. (Unitid 61)
  - Homily of St. Michael for the 12th of Genbot (May 20) by John Bishop of Ethiopia, 1800s; multiple folios; Located on folio 130v-136r. (Unitid 61)
    - A Miracle of St. Michael, 1800s; multiple folios; Located on folio 136r-138v. (Unitid 61)
    - Synaxarium Entry for the 12th of Genbot, 1800s; multiple folios; Located on folio 138v-139r. (Unitid 61)
  - Homily of St. Michael for the 12th of Nahasē (Aug. 18), 1800s; multiple folios; Located on folio 140r-147r. (Unitid 61)
    - A Miracle of St. Michael, 1800s; multiple folios; Located on folio 147r-149v. (Unitid 61)
    - Synaxarium Entry for the 12th of Nahasē, 1800s; multiple folios; Located on folio 149v. (Unitid 61)
  - Commemoration of the Feast Day of the Archangel Raphael on the 3rd of P'āgumē[n] (Sept. 7), 1800s; multiple folios; Located on folio 150r-154r. (Unitid 61)
  - Homily of St. Michael for the 12th of Maskaram (Sept. 22), 1800s; multiple folios; Located on folio 155r-158v. (Unitid 61)
    - A Miracle of St. Michael, 1800s; multiple folios; Located on folio 158v-161r. (Unitid 61)
    - Synaxarium Entry for the 12th of Maskaram, 1800s; multiple folios; Located on folio 161rv. (Unitid 61)
  - Homily of St. Michael for the 12th of T'eqemt (Oct. 22), 1800s; multiple folios; Located on folio 162v-168r. (Unitid 61)
    - Two Miracles of St. Michael, 1800s; multiple folios; Located on folio 168r-174v. (Unitid 61)
    - Synaxarium Entry for the 12th of T'eqemt, 1800s; multiple folios; Located on folio 174v-176v. (Unitid 61)
  - [Different hand] Malke' Hymn to the Archangel Michael, 1800s; multiple folios; Located on folio 177v-183v. (Unitid 61)
    Attributed to Hēnok the son of Yārēd, concluding with a colophon dating the completion of this part of the manuscript to the month of Maskaram 1913 EC, equivalent to September 1920.
- Princeton Ethiopic Manuscript No. 62: Psalter, 1800s; 62; 135 folios 1 column [fols. 1-120r], 2 columns [120v-135], 25 lines. Parchment. No cover, stitched (some folios loose). 13 x 20 cm (Unitid 62)
  - Book of Psalms, 1800s; multiple folios; Located on folio 1r-103r. (Unitid 62)
  - Canticles of the Prophets, 1800s; multiple folios; Located on folio 103r-114r. (Unitid 62)
  - Song of Songs, 1800s; multiple folios; Located on folio 114v-120r. (Unitid 62)
  - Praise of Mary, Wəddase Maryam (Weddāsē Māryām), for Each of the Days of the Week, 1800s; multiple folios; Located on folio 120v-130v. (Unitid 62)
  - The Shorter Office of the Virgin Mary (Anqas'a Berhān or Gate of Light), 1800s; multiple folios; Located on folio 130v-135v. (Unitid 62)
- Princeton Ethiopic Manuscript No. 63: Fragments of the Homilies of St. Michael, and Other Texts, circa 1770-1830; 63; 88 folios 2 columns, 22-24 lines. Wooden boards, stitched with open spine. Fols. 17r, 83r: Blank 18 x 22.5 cm (Unitid 63)
  The rubrics and thus the titles of most texts are faded and illegible. The text is fragmented and the individual elements do not follow the normal sequence.
  The manuscript is severely damaged after fol. 82v and identifying the texts is difficult; there are however sections (e.g. a Synaxarium entry) pertaining to the month of Maskaram.
  - Introduction to the Homilies and Miracles of St. Michael (Incomplete), circa 1770-1830; multiple folios; Located on folio 1rv. (Unitid 63)
  - [Different hand] Continuation of the Previous, circa 1770-1830; multiple folios; Located on folio 2r-3r. (Unitid 63)
  - Synaxarium Entry (Date Unspecified) for St. Michael, circa 1770-1830; multiple folios; Located on folio 3r. (Unitid 63)
    - A Miracle of St. Michael, circa 1770-1830; multiple folios; Located on folio 3v-7r. (Unitid 63)
  - Synaxarium Entry for the 12th of Genbot, circa 1770-1830; multiple folios; Located on folio 7v. (Unitid 63)
    - A Miracle of St. Michael, circa 1770-1830; multiple folios; Located on folio 7v-8v. (Unitid 63)
    - Homily of St. Michael for the 12th of Genbot, circa 1770-1830; multiple folios; Located on folio 8v-10v. (Unitid 63)
  - Homily of St. Michael by John Bishop of Axum, circa 1770-1830; multiple folios; Located on folio 11r-14r. (Unitid 63)
    - A Miracle of St. Michael, circa 1770-1830; multiple folios; Located on folio 14r-16r. (Unitid 63)
    - Synaxarium Entry for the 12th of Hedār (Incomplete), circa 1770-1830; multiple folios; Located on folio 16rv. (Unitid 63)
  - [Different hand] Treatise on the Four Gospels, circa 1770-1830; multiple folios; Located on folio 17v-21r. (Unitid 63)
  - A Miracle of St. Michael, circa 1770-1830; multiple folios; Located on folio 21r-26v. (Unitid 63)
  - Homily of St. Michael by By Abbā Damātēwos of Alexandria (I.e. for the Month of Hedār), circa 1770-1830; multiple folios; Located on folio 27r-30r. (Unitid 63)
  - Homily of St. Michael (Unidentified, Possibly for the Month of T'er), circa 1770-1830; multiple folios; Located on folio 30v-44r. (Unitid 63)
  - Synaxarium Entry for the 12th of T'er, circa 1770-1830; multiple folios; Located on folio 44rv. (Unitid 63)
    - A Miracle of St. Michael, circa 1770-1830; multiple folios; Located on folio 44v-45v. (Unitid 63)
  - Homily of St. Michael for the 12th of Yakkātit, circa 1770-1830; multiple folios; Located on folio 45v-53v. (Unitid 63)
  - Synaxarium Entry for the 12th of Maggābit, circa 1770-1830; multiple folios; Located on folio 54r. (Unitid 63)
    - A Miracle of St. Michael, circa 1770-1830; multiple folios; Located on folio 54r-55r. (Unitid 63)
  - Homily of St. Michael (Unspecified), circa 1770-1830; multiple folios; Located on folio 55r-61r. (Unitid 63)
  - [Different hand] History of St. Michael for Reading on the 12th of Sanē, circa 1770-1830; multiple folios; Located on folio 61r-65v. (Unitid 63)
  - A Miracle of St. Michael, circa 1770-1830; multiple folios; Located on folio 66rv. (Unitid 63)
  - Homily of St. Michael for the Month of Hamlē by Bishop John, circa 1770-1830; multiple folios; Located on folio 66v-68v. (Unitid 63)
  - Homily of St. Michael for the 12th of Maggābit, circa 1770-1830; multiple folios; Located on folio 69r-70r. (Unitid 63)
  - Synaxarium Entry for the 12th of Yakkātit, circa 1770-1830; multiple folios; Located on folio 70r-71r. (Unitid 63)
  - Homily of St. Michael (Unspecified), circa 1770-1830; multiple folios; Located on folio 71r-75v. (Unitid 63)
  - Part of a Different Homily of St. Michael (Beginning Missing), circa 1770-1830; multiple folios; Located on folio 76r-78r. (Unitid 63)
  - Synaxarium Entry for the 12th of Hamlē, circa 1770-1830; multiple folios; Located on folio 78rv. (Unitid 63)
  - A Miracle of St. Michael, circa 1770-1830; multiple folios; Located on folio 78v-79r. (Unitid 63)
  - Homily of St. Michael for the Month of Nahāsē, circa 1770-1830; multiple folios; Located on folio 79r-81v. (Unitid 63)
    - Synaxarium Entry for the 12th of Nahāsē, circa 1770-1830; multiple folios; Located on folio 81v. (Unitid 63)
  - A Miracle of St. Michael, circa 1770-1830; multiple folios; Located on folio 82v. (Unitid 63)
- Princeton Ethiopic Manuscript No. 64: Fragment of a Hymnary for the Divine Office (Deggwā), circa 1850-1899; 64; 6 folios 3 columns, 40 lines. Loose folios. Fols. 4-6: Blank 25 x 31 cm (Unitid 64)
  - Fragment of the Deggwā (Hymnary for the Divine Office) Containing Hymns and Troparies for the Divine Office, With Cantillation Signs, circa 1850-1899; multiple folios; Located on folio 1r-3r. (Unitid 64)